Jesse Martinez Software Developer

Prior United States Marine who found a passion in technology. I started pursuing programming in free courses online which eventually landed me in a coding boot camp that turned me into a Software Developer. My past military experience aided me throughout my past jobs with attention to detail, leadership experience, initiative to work, and the ability to always push forward for new knowledge.

Education

2020-01 -2020-05 Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Web Development

Digital Crafts - Houston, TX

2017-01 -Current Some College (No Degree): Computer Science And Programming

Houston Community College - Houston, TX

• Continuing education in Computer Science

2011-01 -2015-01 **High School Degree**

Alief Taylor High School - Houston, Texas

Programming Projects

<u>MeetMeHalfway - https://github.com/JesseMart/API-Project.git</u>

- Uses Google Maps API, HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JavaScript
- Allows users in the Houston area to meet halfway between both of their addresses. It's measured by driving time, and returns local restaurant around the halfway mark in a certain radius.
- Uses the Zomato API
- The Zomato API connects to the Google Maps
 API and creates an algorithm to find the nearby restaurants within the set radius
- Hosted one a live AWS S3 web server.
- This project was completed with 3 other developers.

Contact

Address

Houston, TX

Phone

(832) 953-8022

E-mail

jessemartinez452@gmail. com

WWW

https://github.com /JesseMart

Software Skills

HTML 5

JavaScript ES6

React

Node.is

BootStrap 4

CSS 3

JQuery

Amazon Web Services

Express.js

PostgreSQL

Sequelize

Python

<u>Favorite Music Artist Website</u> - https://github.com/JesseMart/musicApp.git

- Website including information, current album and songs info for the artist "The Weeknd"
- Includes an active feedback page.
- Uses Node.js, Javascript.js and JSON data.
 BlackjackGame https://github.com/JesseMart

/blackjack_game.git

- Uses JavaScript, HTML 5 and CSS 3
- Uses multiple functions calls to create the cards, deal the cards, shuffle the cards, etc.

RPG Game - https://github.com/JesseMart /rpg-hero.git

- My very first project where a Hero (You) fights an random enemy
- The user has an option to choose whether or not to fight the enemy
- Uses primarily Python
- Uses only **Python**

Work History

United States Marine Corp, Houston, Texas
As an enlisted of an AAV (Amphibious Assault
Vehicle Crewman unit, we performed various
duties to maintain and operate our vehicle as well
as the weapons mounted on the vehicle.
Crewman prepare AAV's for the tactical
deployment of troops and equipment during ship
to shore movement and subsequent operations
ashore.

2018-08 - **Swim Instructor** 2019-01

Goldfish Swim School & Goldfish Swim School Franchising LLC, Houston, Texas

- Learned and maintained proficiency in first responder skills such as First Aid and CPR to offer individuals in distress optimal support.
- Tracked students' progress and gave constructive feedback for skills requiring improvement.

Redux

Flexbox

API's

Debugging

Languages

Spanish